■
本字幕由
ShinY深影字幕组
原创译制
深影字幕组论坛
http://shinybbs.vip
你好 督察
Hello, Inspector.
你好 伙计
Aye, mate.
早上好 公爵
G' morning, Duke.
早上好 乔治
G' morning George.
■
|
- 早上好 督察 - 克里斯汀先生
- Morning inspector. - Mr Christian.
给
Here ya' go...
好的
OK.
有什么情况吗
Anything I need to know?
没有
No...
今日无事 公爵
Not today, Duke.
继续留神
Well, keep your eyes peeled.
又是新的一天 薇尔莉特
And a new day, Violet.
- 弗雷德里克 - 公爵
- Frederick. - Duke.
伦敦大都会警察厅
苏格兰场
早上好 长官
Morning, sir.
是要开会吗
Do we have a meeting?
坐下
Sit down.
有什么问题吗 长官
Do we have a problem, sir?
坐下再说
Take a seat, aye?
我呢... 知道咱俩并非事事相投
Now... I know we've not always seen eye to eye,
但我尽量不让个人情绪
but I try not to let personal feelings
影响到专业决策
get in the way of professional decisions.
因此 我要引荐你到一个更高的职位
Which is why I'm recommending you for a promotion.
长官
Sir?
总督察的位置空了出来
A vacancy for Chief Inspector has come up.
经我大力举荐 这位子是你的了
I put a good one in for you. The job is yours.
非常感谢您 长官
Well, thank you very much, sir.
毕竟你的成绩也该得到嘉奖了
Well, it's about time you received the recognition you deserve.
- 做得不错 小伙子 - 多谢
- Well done, laddie. - Thank you.
谢谢 长官
Thank you, sir.
薪水也会跟着涨一些
There will be a few more pennies in the bank too.
具体多少还得和麦克尼尔警司商量 不过...
We'll need to talk that through with Superintendent McNeill... but uh...
怎么是麦克尼尔警司
Why Superintendent McNeill?
新职位在格拉斯哥警队
Promotion is to the Glasgow Force,
你这个月底就出发
you'll be leaving end of the month.
格拉斯哥警队
The Glasgow Force?
回老家的感觉不错吧
Nice to get back to the old hometown.
再次表扬 小伙子
Well done again, laddie.
长官
Sir...
请容我些时间考虑一下
I would like some time to think about it.
我要去曼彻斯特几天
Well, I'm off to Manchester for a couple of days.
等我回来再告诉我
Give me an answer when I get back.
翻译  Gemma
翻译  二阶堂盛义
翻译  Stoic
翻译  璐璐有为
翻译  凌大
校对&后期  飒白恬
斯嘉丽小姐和公爵
第二季 第五集
- 维克多·拉奇曼先生 - 没有
- Mr. Victor Latchman. - None.
- 亚历山大·李普顿勋爵 - 没有
- Lord Alexander Lipton. - No.
巴斯侯爵 托马斯·彭布罗克爵士
Sir Thomas Pembroke, Marquis of Bath.
都没有
No, nothing.
他们就没有一丁点丑闻吗
Not a single piece of scandal on any of them?
那位李普顿的叔叔最近在镇上没少花钱
Well, the uncle of the Lipton man has been throwing his money around town.
都花哪了
On what?
医院
To hospitals.
还有一个专为穷人制衣的工厂
And a factory making clothes for the poor.
他们已经这样好几周了
They've been doing this for weeks now.
你关心他们的行踪做什么
Why you care what they've been up to?
帕克夫人花钱雇我调查
Mrs. Parker pays me to do background checks
那些可能成为他侄女婿的人
on potential husbands for her niece.
她想看看他们够不够格
She wants to know if they're suitable.
而我向哈蒂保证过 会挑些他们的毛病
And I promised Hattie to find reasons why they are unsuitable.
她想要嫁给自己选择的人 但她的姑妈...
She wishes to marry someone of her own choosing, and her aunt...
这种揭人老底的活 你还是另寻他人吧
Well, you need to find someone else to do your yard digging.
我不干了
I'm done.
我知道这不太道德 可哈蒂不想再被束缚了
I know it's unethical, but Hattie has had such a sheltered life.
我不在乎道不道德
I don't care about the ethics.
这事太无聊了
it's boring.
无聊
Boring?
那些人都一样 一样的家世一样的生活
They're all the same men with the same families and the same lives.
我可以用这些时间做更值得的事
There are better uses of my time.
我也是有名声的人
I have a reputation to protect.
你是想让我加钱吗
Is this you asking for more money?
不是 这事关职业尊严
No. It'd be about professional pride.
什么意思
Why?
你要给多少
How much are you offering?
你说得对
You're right.
我们的时间得用来做更重要的事
There are much better uses of our time.
我现在就去找哈蒂
I'm seeing Hattie presently.
让她和姑妈好好聊聊
I will tell her to speak to her aunt.
我倒也乐意和帕克夫人聊上一二
I'm happy to have a word with Mrs Parker myself
如果钱够的话
if the money is right.
这才是我想要的嘛
Now, that is something I would love to see.
亨利·斯嘉丽先生
私家侦探事务所
督察
Inspector.
摩西
Moses.
他来这里做什么
What does he want?
我们在合力调查一件案子
We're working a case together.
什么案子
What kind of case?
换新背心了
Is that a new waistcoat?
挺精干的
Very smart.
没有
No.
你知道自己一不想谈什么事
Are you aware how often you change the subject
就会转移话题吗
when you don't wish to talk about something?
你来得正好 我有事要你帮忙
I'm glad you are here I have a favor to ask.
我说中了吧
Point proved then.
你周四晚上有安排吗
Do you have plans on Thursday evening?
艾薇非要请波茨先生 是巴拿巴先生 来吃晚餐
Ivy is insisting that Mr Potts, or Barnabas, comes to dinner.
我一个人可应付不来
There's no way I can handle that alone.
- 伊莱莎 - 求你了 帮帮忙
- Eliza? - Please, please his on own anyway.
先不说这个了 我...
Never mind that I um...
我得和你说点事
I need to speak to you about something.
你介意我一边聊一边叫个马车吗
Do you mind if I hail a cab while we talk?
哈蒂·帕克一直打电话催 我快迟到了
Hattie Parker is calling around and I'm running late.
可以... 好的
Yes... fine.
是这样
So, um.
今早我上班的时候
So I was at work this morning.
不会是摩西的事吧
This isn't going to be about Moses, is it?
不 和摩西无关
No, it is not about Moses.
虽然你坚持和那些已知罪犯来往
Even though you insist on associateing with known criminals.
- 还真是摩西的事 - 我不是来和你聊摩西的
- This is about Moses. - I didn't come here to speak to you about Moses.
也不是该死的巴拿巴或波茨
Or Barnabas bloody Potts.
我...
I've...
我升职了
I've been offered a promotion.
- 总督察 - 威廉
- Chief Inspector. - William.
这是天大的好消息
That's wonderful news.
恭喜你了
Congratulations.
职位在格拉斯哥
The job is in Glasgow.
我明白了
Oh, I see.
太可惜了
That's a shame.
算了
Never mind.
你不说点别的吗
Is that all you are going to say?
还能说什么
What else is there to say?
那是在格拉斯哥
Well it is in Glasgow.
苏格兰联盟城之一
Allies of Scotland.
我自然知道格拉斯哥在哪儿
I'm well aware where Glasgow is.
很显然你不打算接受 所以...
You're plainly not going to take it. So...
你怎么知道
How do you know?
威廉 我作为朋友这么说
William, I say this as a friend.
自从我认识你
Since I've known you.
你面临过很多工作机会
You've been offered many different jobs.
只要不是在伦敦
Any that are outside of London,
你都会推掉
You've always turned down.
确实 但这次是升到总督察
Yes, but this is a promotion to Chief Inspector.
我没记错的话 和诺丁汉那次一样
As for the job in Nottingham, I seem to remember.
这种谈话我们已经有过不下三次了
We've had this conversation on at least three occasions.
你每次都是痛苦挣扎一番
And each time you agonize over the decision
最后选择留下
and in the end you decide to stay.
何必呢 反正你在这里过得很舒坦
And why not? You're "comfortable" here.
舒坦
Comfortable?
我没措好词
It was a poor choice of words.
告诉你吧 我是真的考虑要接下这份工作
For your information, I'm seriously thinking about taking this job.
没错 这句话我之前也说过
And yes, I'm well aware that I've said that before.
威廉
William!
你姑妈又给了我一份候选丈夫名单
Your aunt has given me yet another list of potential husbands.
我快找不到他们不适合的理由了
I'm running out of reasons as to why are unsuitable.
哈蒂 你必须和她说明白
You must speak to her, Hattie,
告诉她你暂且不想成婚
and tell her you do not wish to marry yet.
可我并非不想结婚
It is not that I do not wish to marry.
只是不想与一个不情不愿的人结婚
It's just... I do not wish to marry someone who does not wish to marry me.
- 你想为爱而婚 - 是的...
- You want to marry for love. - Yes...
但姑妈觉得我太天真
but my aunt thinks I'm fanciful.
她说 "哈蕊特 你的年纪和容貌
'Harriet', she says, 'You do not have the luxury of time,'
已经等不起真爱了"
'or looks to wait for love.'
她如何明白得了
How could she possibly understand?
大家都爱她
Everyone is in love with her.
你是成年女性
You're a grown woman.
- 必须为自己争取 - 我也在努力
- You must stand up for yourself. - I do try.
但你无法想象 她执着得简直...
but you'd be surprised how determined she can be...
和你一样
...as you.
你是个迷人的女士
You are a lovely young woman.
任何男人娶了你都是他们的福气
Any man would be lucky to have you as their wife.
- 你这么觉得 - 当然
- Do you think so? - Absolutely.
我会告诉姑妈 我不想结婚
I will tell my aunt I do not wish to wed.
就此打住
And that is that.
爹爹给我留了一些钱
Papa left me some money.
也许我可以出去自力更生
Perhaps I could set up my own house.
可能要走一些财务手续 但如你所说 伊莱莎
There may be financial implications, but as you say, Eliza,
我是个成年女性 我会找到出路的
I'm a grown woman and I will find a way.
我会吧
Won't I?
会的
You will.
我要去找家庭会计 诺里斯先生
I will go and see Mr Norris, our family accountant.
他会告诉我姑妈控制了哪部分财产
He will tell me which purse strings my aunt controls.
这算个计划
So that is a plan.
算吗
Is it?
算啊
It is.
你能和我一起去吗
Will you come with me?
我有十足的信心 你能独立完成此事
I have every faith that you can do this on your own.
- 你不和我去吗 - 没错
- So that is a definite no? - Yes.
- 你不会改变主意了 - 不改变
- And you will not change your mind? - No.
谢谢你改变主意
Thank you for changing your mind.
和诺里斯先生交谈一定要注意
You must be careful what to say to Mr Norris.
他对我姑妈可谓是痴迷
He's rather enamored with my aunt.
真的吗
Really?
是啊 她有许多倾慕者
Oh, yes. She has many admirers.
她是一位美丽端庄的女士
She's a very handsome woman.
她为何孤身一人依然是个谜
It's a mystery how she remains alone.
Norris及合伙人
会计
诺里斯先生
Mr Norris?
- 我在这儿等着 - 你确定不进去吗
- I'll wait here. - You sure you do not want to come in?
诺里斯先生
Mr Norris?
我是帕克 诺里斯先生
It's Miss Parker.  Mr Norris?
诺里斯先生
Mr Norris?
报警吧
Fetch the police.
现在就报 哈蒂
Now Hattie!
尸僵在死后二小时左右出现
Rigor mortis sets in about 2 hours after death
先从面部和下颌部的肌肉开始
first with the muscles around the face and jaw
继而蔓延至全身
and then it progresses outwards to the rest of the body.
这场景再熟悉不过了
This all feels so very familiar.
斯嘉丽小姐 我记得请你陪着帕克小姐
Miss Scarlet, I seem to remember asking you to accompany Miss Parker
返回警察厅作一下陈词来着
back to Scotland Yard to give a statement.
不只是似曾相识... 而是精心上演
not just familiar... but "staged".
为何如此大费周章呢
But why go to all the effort?
检查一下他的手腕
Try moving his wrists.
完全僵直
Completely rigid.
尸体呈现完全僵直需要14-18个小时
Full rigor mortis takes 14 to 18 hours to develop,
死亡时间应为昨晚的某个时刻
which puts the time of death at some point last night.
当然只是个大致区间
It's only a rough guide of course,
- 具体时间仍未可知 - 午夜前一刻
- we can't tell the exact time. - A quarter to Midnight.
看来我结论下早了
I stand corrected.
斯嘉丽小姐显然已经掌握了
Miss Scarlet clearly has developed a new technique
超越当今医学的新技术
unknown to medical science.
这技术叫"睁亮你的大眼"
It's called using your eyes.
时钟被拨停了
The clock has been stopped.
不 它确实停了
No, it has stopped.
- 你无法确定它是不是被拨停的 - 威廉
- You do not know it has been stopped. - William.
叫我威灵顿督查
Inspector Wellington.
这里的场景与小说中并无二致
This entire scene is exactly as it was in the novel.
哪本小说
What novel?
《午夜前一刻》 萨缪尔·贝德伯勒写的
A Quarter to Midnight by Samuel Bedborough.
- 你知道吗 - 没听说过
- You heard about it? - No.
请赐教
Enlighten me.
距我读这本小说已有数年
For a few years since I read it, I would swear
但我发誓眼前的一切恰与书中所述相同
everything in this room is precisely as it was in the book.
染血的百合
The Bloodstained lily,
颈中的匕首
the knife in the neck,
死者手在胸前的位置
the arrangement of his hand on his chest,
以及时钟所停留的时刻
and the clock stopped at a quarter to midnight.
你真该多读读书
You really should read more.
我读得可多了 唯独就差这本
I read plenty, just not that particular book.
我也没读过
I've not read it either.
谢谢你 菲茨罗伊警探
Thank you, Detective Fitzroy.
不过我确实一周至少读一本
Although I do read at least one book a week.
俄国批判现实主义作家
我最近在研究俄国文学 读伊凡·冈察洛夫
At the moment I'm working through the Russian study, Ivan Goncharov.
该干嘛干嘛吧
Go make yourself useful.
搜一下有没有来宾签名簿或者预约日程表
See if there's a visitor's book or a list of his appointments.
找出他最后见的谁
find out who was last in here.
斯嘉丽小姐... 借一步说话
Miss Scarlet... a word?
回警察厅吧
Go back to Scotland Yard.
作一下陈词
Make a statement.
但我在这儿更能帮上忙吧
But I can be of much more use here.
你能照我说的去做吗
Will you just do what I ask?
是因为你的新任命吧
This is about your job offer, isn't it?
我刚说的话让你不高兴了
You're annoyed with what I said.
伊莱莎 你的言语常常让我不高兴
Eliza, I am so often annoyed with what you've said,
我不知道你指的是哪句
it's hard to keep track.
我说你"过得舒坦"那句
When I said you were comfortable.
你其实想说我没有上进心
You meant I lacked ambition.
不 当然不是
No, of course not.
只是说你的人生已按照喜好安排好了
Only that your life is arranged as you like it.
你已经安于现状了
You're settled.
这比说我"舒坦"还不中听
That sounds even more insulting than comfortable.
我觉得最好换个话题
I think it's best if we cease to discuss this.
我做好决定后会告诉你的
I will let you know my decision when I have come to it.
- 行吧 但我就想说... - 别
- All right, but can I just say...  - No.
现在回警察厅
Now go back to Scotland Yard
找菲尔普斯
and ask for Phelps.
那本小说
That book.
您认为凶手拿来模仿杀人的那本小说
The one you think the murderer imitated.
您刚才说这书是萨缪尔·贝德伯勒写的
You said it was from by Samuel Bedborough.
没错啊 怎么了
That's right. Why?
死者生前是他的会计
The victim was his accountant.
我没觉得哪里不行啊
I do not see what the problem is.
- 我不会雇你的 - 听我把话说完
- I'm not hiring you.  - Just hear me out.
首先
Firstly,
我读过萨缪尔·贝德伯勒写的每一本小说
I've read every Samuel Bedborough novel,
他的作品令我沉迷不已
I'm a huge fan of his work.
其次
Secondly,
如果你不雇我 哈蒂·帕克肯定会雇我
if you don't hire me, Hattie Parker surely will.
诺里斯先生正是她姑姑的朋友
Mr Norris was a friend of her aunt.
共享情报和资源当然更好了
Surely it's better to share information and resources,
不为我 也请为伦敦的纳税人考虑下吧
and if not for me but then for the taxpayers of London.
你可真是大公无私啊 伊莱莎
Oh, you're so selfless, Eliza.
这是我的天职啊
It is a cross I must bear.
那... 就这么说定了
So... is that a yes?
费用是多少呢
How much is your fee?
我转念一想 咱们别讨价还价了
On second thoughts, let's forgo the haggling
直接考虑你说的数目吧
and think of the first amount you were going to say.
听起来还算公平
That seems fair.
好
Good.
现在折半
Now halve that.
威洛比书店
他专注于某个目标的时候
He could not be distracted
总是心无旁骛
once his mind was focused on a task.
没有什么能打断他的思绪
There was nothing that could break his chain of thought,
楼下窗户的破碎声不能
not the shattering of the window downstairs,
过道里的脚步声亦不能
not the footsteps in the hallway.
最终他抬头仰望
When at last he looked up,
却看见一柄利刃在冷月下寒光四射
he saw a blade glistening in the moonlight
然后感受到心脏处冰冷而尖锐的刺痛
and felt the cold steel pierce his heart.
第三章
Thus concludes
结束
Chapter three.
太感谢了 贝德伯勒先生
Thank you, Mr. Bedborough
又一次用一场精彩绝伦的读书会
for once again gracing our humble shop
使敝店蓬荜生辉
with such a wonderful reading.
现在 如果各位愿意排队等候
Now, if you would like to form an orderly queue,
贝德伯勒先生将欣然在作品上题名
Mr Bedborough will gladly sign copies of his book
当然要是在本店购买的作品
as long as they have been purchased here of course.
不行 不行
No, no, no.
不能进
Outside please...
我要找贝德伯勒先生说几句话...
I need to speak to Mr Bedborough...
今天的活动凭票入场
This event is for ticket holders only.
我是警察厅的威灵顿督查
I'm inspector Wellington of Scotland Yard.
我在执行警察公务
I'm here on police business.
但您还带着夫人呢
And yet you brought your wife.
她不是我太太
She's not my wife.
我是协助警察厅办案的私家侦探
I am a private detective assisting Scotland Yard with their inquiries.
我听过很多种借口 但这个...
I've heard many excuses in my time, but that...
我的神呐 他的破书我一本都没读过
Oh for God's sake, I haven't even read any of his damn books.
我读过
I have.
我是贝德伯勒
I am Ms Bedborough,
萨缪尔的妹妹
Samuel's sister.
请问有什么事吗
Is something wrong?
我需要马上跟您哥哥谈谈
I need to speak to your brother right away.
这是什么时候的事
When did this happen?
我们确信 诺里斯先生是昨晚遇害的
We believe Mr Norris was killed last night.
你能想到谁会加害于他吗
Can you think of anyone who might wish to do him harm?
他是个很正派的好人
He always seem to be a perfectly decent man.
说实话 我对他了解不多
In truth, I didn't know him well.
他只是业务上的熟人
He was a business acquaintance.
我们一年只见几次面
We only met a few times a year.
上一次是什么时候呢
When was the last time?
几周前了
A few weeks ago.
我说不好
I couldn't say for sure.
正如我们说的
As we mentioned,
我们认为案发现场是依照
we believe the crime scene was arranged
《午夜前一刻》里的凶案场景布置的
to resemble the murders in Quarter to Midnight.
真想不到
How extraordinary.
你理解
You understand that
我必须确认昨晚你的行踪  那么...
I have to ask you about your own movements last night, so...
为什么
Why?
这是例行询问  萨缪尔
It's a standard question, Samuel.
他们每个人都会问
They ask it of everyone.
我在布拉汉姆酒店开了间套房
I have a suite in Brabham hotel.
昨晚我在那儿写最新的小说呢
I'm staying there whilst I finish my latest novel.
你是独处吗
And were you alone?
你说除了那五十名店员和三百名客人
You mean apart from the 50 staff and 300 guests.
萨缪尔
Samuel.
我和我妹妹用了晚餐 然后我整晚都在写作
My sister and I had dinner and then I wrote all night.
交稿都交晚了
I'm rather late delivering my latest novel.
你曾经在去出版社的马车上完成一部书稿
Is it true you once finished a manuscript in the carriage
这是真的吗
on the way to the publishers?
我厌恶交稿日
I woeful about deadlines,
但我不需要灵感和氛围
but I have no need for Muse or Mood.
我在任何时间地点都能够创作
I can write any time or any place.
你喜欢我的小说
You enjoy my novels?
非常喜欢 非常
Very much so, yes.
实际上 《午夜前一刻》是我的最爱
In fact, Quarter to Midnight is my favorite.
我还没读过那本 但是呢...
Oh, I haven't read that particular one, but...
我很喜欢《深红阴影的诅咒》
I did enjoy Curse of the Crimson Shadow.
那不是我写的
That was not me.
《午夜前一刻》
Quarter to Midnight.
情节基于贝德伯勒的个人经历
It's based on Bedborough's own life.
他多年来写的作品从未获得发表
He spent years as an unpublished writer
直到最后一举获得成功
before finally enjoying success.
小说里的主人公
Writer in the novel is
也是在巨大压力下完成最新小说的创作
under pressure to deliver his latest book
然后逐渐步入疯癫
and slowly starts going insane.
认为他最好的两个朋友要把他送入精神病院
Believes his two best friends want to put him in an asylum
所以他把他们都杀了
so he kills them both.
但和麦克白一样 他无法带着内疚生活下去
But like Macbeth, he is unable to live with the guilt.
你知道麦克白吧
You do know the story of...
伊莱莎 我当然知道麦克白的故事
Yes, Eliza, I know the story of Macbeth.
真是不好意思
My apologies.
总之
Anyway,
小说里的那位作家还是孩子时
when the author in the novel was a child,
他的父母由于猩红热双双过世
his parents died of scarlet fever.
还是个孩子的他
As a boy, he witnessed them
看着父母躺在家里的棺材中
laid out in their coffins at home,
两人手里都拿着一只百合花
each holding a lily.
诺里斯办公室里的时钟停在午夜前一刻
The clock in Norris' office read about a quarter to midnight,
正是书中两场谋杀案发生的时间
which is the exact time of two murders in the book take place,
不过是在不同的晚上进行
but on separate nights.
所以说 如果有人如此渴望再现书中情节
So if someone is that keen to replicate the book
很有可能会再次杀人
then it is possible they could kill again.
对 是有可能
It's possible. Yes.
我们还有更多有关受害者的信息吗
Do we know any more about our victim?
爱德华·诺里斯 五十二岁
Edward Norris, 52 years old,
未婚 是一位受人尊敬的会计 客户一百位左右
unmarried, he's a respectable accountant with hundred or so clients
我们正在一一排查
that we're busy tracking down.
我再把书看一遍吧
I'm going to read the book again.
看有没有漏掉什么信息
See if there's anything we've missed.
你是否也能看一遍呢
May I suggest you do the same?
菲茨罗伊
Fitzroy?
把你目前掌握的有关诺里斯与其业务伙伴的信息全部给我
Give me everything you have so far on Norris and his associates.
马上办 长官
Right away, sir.
对了 把《麦克白》的故事大纲也给我一份
Oh, and give me a brief synopsis on the story of Macbeth.
几页就好
A couple of pages should do it.
马上给您 长官
You will have it, sir.
《麦克白》中的经典台词
"待到硝烟散尽 战斗胜负已定"
When the hurly burly is done, when the battle's lost and won.
还是一页吧
...make that one page.
是 长官
Yes, sir.
威洛比书店
午夜前一刻
SAMUEL BEDBOROUGH著
这是贝德伯勒先生最有名的作品
This is Mr Bedborough's most famous work.
但您是否考虑先从《独行格林威治》开始读呢
but have you considered beginning with Alone in Greenwich,
应该就在这里
which should be here somewhere?
没错
Yes.
我把这本看完就看 威洛比女士
I'll read that straight after this, Miss Willoughby.
我可以推荐您先看它吗
Might I recommend that you read it first?
它们简直天生一对
They do make a wonderful pair.
如此生动的散文
Such vivid prose.
每一行我都能倒背如流
I could recite every line.
我还是先看这本吧
I think I'll just start with this one for now.
哎呀 我在说什么呢
You know, what am I saying?
我还推荐《锯齿状裂痕》
I would also recommend The Jagged Tear
其实
In fact,
我应该直接把他的全集都给您
But perhaps I should just get you his complete works.
- 听起来如何 - 价格不菲
- How does that sound? - Expensive.
我能否问问
May I ask...
您为什么要找贝德伯勒先生问话
why you wanted to speak to Mr Bedborough?
恕我无可奉告
I can't discuss that I am afraid.
他一来我就发现不对劲
I knew there was something wrong as soon as he came in.
他一般都是兴高采烈地来参加阅读会的
He usually turns up to readings in a wonderful mood.
但今天的他
But today he was
很不在状态 有些沮丧
rather withdrawn and upset.
- 我与他谈话前就是这样吗 - 是的
- And this was before I spoke to him. - Yes.
我从来没见过他这样
I've never seen him like that before.
希望一切都好
I do hope everything is all right.
需要把它们包装起来吗
Would you like them wrapped?
喝一杯吗 长官
Wanna have one, skipper?
不了 我要集中精神看书
Naw, I'm trying to concentrate.
还是给你搞了一杯
Got you one anyway.
不像你啊
Not like you.
是为了那个诺里斯案
It is for the Norris case,
感觉你不像是会看书的
Did not have you down as much of a reader,
更像是喜欢运动的
but from the sporting past.
你需要什么吗 查理
You want something, Charlie?
没 就看看你怎么样
No. Just seeing how you are.
有没有什么新闻
If there's any news.
我们一起工作已有十年了
In the ten years we've worked together,
你应该从来没请我喝过一杯
I don't think you've ever bought me a drink.
- 人是会变的嘛 - 人是会变
- People change. - People do.
但你不会
But you don't.
说吧 需要什么
What do you want?
我听到警司说要给你升职
I heard the Superintendent talking to you about a promotion.
- 我就是路过 - 路过
- I was just passing. - Passing?
我就在考虑
And I was thinking
如果你接受了的话
if you did take it,
能不能帮我说几句好话
you might put in a word for me
让我接你的班
to take over from you.
你说话还真是直来直去啊
Now, subtlety never was your strong point was it?
我有妻子和四个孩子要养
I've got a wife and four kids.
五个孩子
Five kids.
哪能绕这么多圈子
I can't afford to be subtle.
我知道你之前有过其他工作机会 你都给拒绝了
I know you've had offers in the past and turned them down.
但时间不等人 我们都会变老
But you're not getting any younger... neither of us are.
到某一时刻机会就不会来找你了 命运就无法改变了
At some point the offers are not coming and that will be your lot.
如果你对现状很满意 那没问题
If you are happy with how things are, fine.
- 但如果你心有不甘 - 我很满意
- But if you're not... - Yes.
谢谢你 警探
Thank you, Detective.
进展如何
Any good?
毫无头绪
Terrible.
午夜前一刻
贝拉米父子出版社
本年度其它体育消息
早上好
Good morning.
早
Morning.
谢谢你 萨米特
Thank you, Sammit.
我在诺里斯案上取得了一些进展
I made some progress in the Norris case...
需要看物证
I need to see the evidence.
你怎么找到我的
How did you find me?
猜得比较准吧
Lucky guess.
其实你生活很有规律
You do have something of a set routine.
周一去本杰明那儿
Benjamin on Monday.
周二去德尔卡普那儿
Delcap on Tuesday.
周三去刷鞋匠那儿
Shoeshine on Wednesday.
周四去
Thursday...
好了好了 知道你什么意思了
Alright, you've made your point.
取得了什么进展
What progress has been made?
我需要看一下凶器
I need to see the murder weapon.
我把《午夜前一刻》又看了一遍
I re-read Quarter to Midnight
我也是 还看了他其他的一些作品
As did I along with some of his other work.
你知道贝德伯勒是在济贫院长大的吗
Did you know Bedborough was raised in a workhouse?
当然
Indeed, yes.
白手起家致富的主题在他的书中十分常见
Themes of rags to riches are very common with his characters.
例如《独行格林威治》里的律师
Like the lawyer in Alone in Greenwich.
威廉 我很惊讶哦 不错嘛
William, I am both surprised and impressed.
一句话里既褒又贬
Compliment and an insult in one.
真有你的 伊莱莎
That's quite something, even for you, Eliza.
你想好了吗 要不要接受那份工作
Have you made your decision yet, about the job?
我和你说过了 想好了会告诉你的
As I said, I'll let you know when I have.
好吧 想和我谈谈的话 我随时欢迎
Well, please feel free to discuss it with me.
然后让你侮辱我 是吗
And let you insult me, yeah?
真是谢谢你呀
Well, thank you.
我没想侮辱你
My intention was not to insult.
有时候你真是敏感
You can be rather sensitive sometimes.
"敏感" "安于现状" 评价真是越来越高了
Sensitive and settled, well this just get better and better.
- 威廉 - 这个案子
- William. - The case...
伊莱莎 你想看凶器
Eliza, you want to see the murder weapon,
书中的凶手两场凶案用的是同一把武器
The killer in Quarter to Midnight uses the same weapon for each murder.
一把刀 没错
The knife... yes.
第一位受害者 颈部被自己的刀刺入
First victim was stabbed in the neck with his own knife.
第二位受害者 颈部插着同一把刀
The second had the same knife embedded in his neck.
我们发现诺里斯时就是这样
which is how we found Norris.
- 也就是说 - 他可能不是第一位受害者
- Which means... - He may not be the first victim.
没错
Exactly.
在这里
Here it is.
昨晚我把书合上时
When I closed the book last night,
在书脊上发现了一样东西
I noticed something on the spine.
出版商贝拉米父子的标徽
The publishers Bellamy & Sons' crest.
是一匹飞驰的骏马
It is a galloping horse.
所以说 如果凶手遵循书中情节
So if the killer is following the plot of the book.
这把刀应该属于第一位受害者
Then the knife belongs to the first victim.
贝拉米父子出版社
锁着的
It's locked.
贝拉米先生
Mr. Bellamy.
有侧门吗
Is there a side entrance?
没时间了
There's no time for that.
踢开它
Kick it down!
上楼看看 什么都别碰
Look upstairs... touch nothing.
威灵顿督察
Inspector Wellington,
在这
in here.
和小说里一样
Just like the novel.
时间也对上了
Right down to the time.
布拉汉姆酒店
汉普顿套房
詹姆斯是个好人
James was a good man.
他做我出版商已经好多年了
He'd been my publisher for years.
你最后一次见到他是什么时候
When did you last see him?
周四晚餐时
At dinner on Thursday night.
他看起来如何
How did he seem?
精神抖擞
In good spirits.
你想不到有谁可能会伤害他吗
And you can think of no one that may wish to do him harm.
我不知道
I don't know.
我的脑子有些混乱
My mind is a little foggy.
我哥哥昨晚在通宵写作
My brother has been up all night writing.
我让他去睡觉 但他从来不听
I tell him to go to bed, but he never listens.
所以你昨晚就在这里吗
And that's where you were last night?
在这间房间里写作
In this room, writing?
是的 一整晚
Yes, all night.
我能问问你手怎么了吗
May I ask what happened to your hand?
老天
God sake!
你非要一直问这些无关紧要的问题吗
Must you keep asking these irrelevant questions?
萨缪尔
Samuel?
我
I... ah...
在浴室里滑倒了
slipped in the bathroom.
我们能待会儿再谈吗
Could we finish this later?
我要去看望詹姆斯的儿子
I must go and visit James's son.
我们认为您还是待在这里好 先生
We prefer you stay here, sir.
这两起谋杀案都和你小说里一模一样
Both murders were exactly as in your novel.
并且你知道 还有第三位死者
And as you know, there is a third death.
我小说里的作者自杀了
The author in my novel takes his own life.
我可以向你保证 我不打算那样做
I can assure you I'm not planning on doing that.
即便如此 如果有人想复刻你的书
Even so, if someone is determined to replicate the book,
它们肯定会想对你下手
they may wish to do you harm.
您妹妹说得对 贝德伯勒先生
Your sister is right, Mr. Bedborough.
如果你想回家的话
I'll arrange police protection for you
我会安排警察来保护你
in the meantime, if you'd like to go home.
我们家在装修
Our home is being decorated.
- 我会待在这的 - 如你所愿
- I'll stay here. - As you wish.
我会在这等到警官来
I'll wait here until an officer arrives.
斯嘉丽小姐
Miss Scarlet,
你方便帮我捎个消息回伦敦警察厅吗
if you could take this message back to Scotland Yard for me.
核查他的不在场证据
我找了夜间门房
I tracked down the night porter.
萨缪尔昨晚九点离开过旅馆
Samuel left the hotel last night around 9 o'clock
直到黎明才回来
and didn't return again until dawn.
一个复刻自己写的书的杀手
A killer who replicates the plot of his own book.
这更像有人想要毁了他的名声
Isn't it more likely that someone is trying to damage his reputation?
可能吧
Possibly.
藏在众目睽睽之下是凶手最好的掩护
There's no better cover than a murderer who hides in plain sight.
他三个月前好像被捕了
It's looks like he was arrested three months ago.
- 因为什么 - 扰乱公共秩序
- What for? - Public Disorder.
他和一个女人在大街上吵架
He was arguing with a woman in the street,
还明目张胆地威胁要杀了对方
and apparently they threatened to kill each other.
他们因妨碍治安被捕
They were arrested for breach of the peace,
但没有受到任何指控
but no charges were brought.
所以警告后就被释放了
So they were cautioned and released.
弗朗切斯卡·贝里希尼
Francesca Bellesini.
她是个演员
She is an actress.
我去停尸房检查尸体 你去和她谈谈
Go and speak to her while I assess the bodies in the mortuary.
斯嘉丽小姐
Miss Scarlet.
打扰了 长官 您的马车在等您了
Excuse me sir. Your carriage is ready.
谢谢你 菲茨罗伊
Thank you, Fitzroy.
我想知道从停尸房回来的路上
On the way back from the mortuary,
位于伦敦西区 剧院与特殊商店是此区的大特色
我们可以经过柯芬园吗
I wonder if we might go via Covent Garden.
奥芬巴赫为法国作曲家
《霍夫曼的故事》是他最后一部歌剧
我很想去买一张奥芬巴赫的
I very much like to get tickets for the premiere of Offenbach's
《霍夫曼的故事》的首映票
The Tales of Hoffmann.
我还是自己找时间去吧
Perhaps I would do that my own time.
最好是这样
Perhaps you will.
如果我走了 他会怎样
What will happen to him if I leave?
好吧 你不接受那份工作是件好事
Well, it's a good that you're not going to take the job...
第几次了
How many times?
我还没有做决定
I haven't made my decision yet.
我不像你 我要考虑我在这建立的生活
Unlike you, I give consideration to the life that I've built here.
"不像我"是什么意思
What do you mean unlike me?
你要是得到这份工作 你只会心跳加速
Well, if you were offered the job, you'd think in a heartbeat.
好吧 当女人可以成为总督察的那天
Well, on the day that women are allowed to be chief inspectors
我们再来一起讨论吧
we should have that conversation.
你懂我什么意思吧
You know what I mean?
如果有人给你更多的钱和高关注度的案子
If you were offered more money and high profile cases,
无论在哪工作 你都一定会抓住机会
you would jump at the chance, no matter the location.
我们是完全不一样的人 威廉
We're very different people, William.
哦 意思是你有远大的抱负
Oh, meaning that you have a singular ambition.
我就是又蠢又好猜的人
And I am a dull and predictable,
- 周一在去学校的路上擦鞋 - 你在曲解我的话
- Monday shoeshine on the way to school... - You're twisting my words.
我有吗
Am I?
你不必向我解释你的生活
You do not have to justify your life to me.
我知道 但你一直拿这个取笑我
I do and you constantly tease me about it.
那我道歉
And I apologize.
显然 我戳中了你的痛处
Clearly, I hit a nerve.
从我的出身来看
From where I have come from,
我能走到这一步已经很好了
I have done damn well to get this far.
不是每个人都有机会继承父亲的事业
We don't all have the luxury of inheriting a father's business.
我要去找贝里希尼小姐说话了
I am going to speak to Miss Bellesini...
我明天早上会收到她的报告
and I'll have her report in the morning.
伊莱莎
Eliza.
Eliza,
我向你道歉
I apologize that...
我没想到 我的话说得太过了
that came out harsher than I expected.
别因为我耽误了你的时间
Don't let me keep you waiting.
三点了 你该喝威士忌了
It's almost time for your 3:00 whiskey.
伦敦大剧院
我是来找贝里希尼小姐的
I'm looking for Miss Bellesini.
弗朗切斯卡·贝里希尼
你和贝德伯勒先生是什么关系
What was the nature of your relationship with Mr Bedborough?
- 我们的关系 - 是的
- The nature of our relationship? - Yes?
性关系
Physical.
你在哪里认识他的
And where did you meet him?
一个聚会上 不记得是谁的了
At some party, cannot remember whose.
但是我们没再见面了
But we do not see each other anymore.
我有新情人了
I have a new lover.
更年轻 更愿意取悦人
Younger, much more willing to please.
你懂的
You know.
你被逮捕那天晚上发生了什么
What happened the night you were arrested?
我喝太多了 去看了他
I had little too much to drink and went to see him.
事情环环相扣
And one thing led to another.
你知道这种事的进展的
You know how these things go.
警察很通情达理
The police were understanding.
我告诉他们这是意大利人的热情
I told them it was Italian passion...
并不是说我来自意大利
not that I am from Italy.
没有人听说过我的国家 所以
Nobody has heard about my country, so...
说意大利更好
Italy plays much better.
所以你跟他吵架是因为他甩了你
So you argue because he finished your relationship?
他送了一条钻石项链给他的小朋友
He sent his little friend with a diamond necklace.
一个分手礼物 让我悄悄走
A parting gift to make me go quietly.
谁是他的朋友
Who was his friend?
诺里斯
Norris.
我想是他的会计
His accountant, I think.
我叫他死神
I call him the Grim Reaper.
你见到他 你就明白死期到了
When you see him, you know it's over.
两起案件的死因相同
Cause of death is identical in both cases.
颈动脉都有一处刺伤
A single puncture wound to the carotid artery.
从伤口大小形状推测是同一把凶器
The size of the wound indicates the same weapon.
你们两个 去会计住的那条街出警
You two, start making house calls on the accountant's street.
看看他有没有什么访客
See if he had any visitors.
菲茨罗伊 菲尔普斯 你们也去出版商那里出警
Fitzroy, Phelps. You do the same for the publisher.
"只要你集中你的全部勇气 我们决不会失败"
Screw your courage to the sticking place and will not fail.
麦克白夫人说的
Lady Macbeth.
我必须跟他一起去吗
Do I have to go with him?
这得看你想不想保住你的工作
That depends whether you want to keep your job.
好了 你们去吧
All right. Off you go.
菲茨罗伊
Fitzroy.
借一步说话
A word, please.
我们所做的工作需要团队合作
What we do requires working as part of a team.
每一个警探 尤其是你
Any detective, you above all,
需要其他同事的信任和尊重
needs the trust and respect of his colleagues,
居然引用莎士比亚
Quoting Shakespeare?
对不起 长官
Sorry, sir.
我说错话了
It was misjudged.
终有一天 我可能无法在身边替你把关
One day I may not be around to look out for you...
- 所以你要开始适应了 - 您要去哪
- so you need to start fitting in. - Where you going?
我只是在说我的观点
I'm just making the point.
跟他们一起去酒吧
Go to the pub with them,
听他们抱怨工作或妻子
then let them moan about their job or their wives
或者在赛马上输的钱
or the money that they lost on the nags.
听他们抱怨我
Let them moan about me.
我永远不会让他们那样做
I would never let them do that.
你越是局外人 越会显得软弱
The more you are an outsider, the weaker you will be.
而像菲尔普斯这样的人 能闻到软弱的味道
And men like Phelps, they can smell weakness,
这并不意味着他是个坏人
no, that doesn't make him a bad man,
这就是警察的天性
It's just the nature of being a copper.
你一定能融入他们 对吧
Surely you can be one of the lads, aye?
您听上去好像我父亲
You sound like my father.
上帝可不允许
God forbid.
很抱歉我迟到了
Sorry for the delay.
我在安慰姑妈
I was comforting my aunt.
她因为诺里斯先生的事很沮丧
She's in great distress about Mr. Norris.
我有一个关于诺里斯先生的问题
Well, I have a question about Mr Norris.
萨缪尔·贝德伯勒说他和诺里斯
Samuel Bedborough said that he and Norris
只是纯粹的工作关系
had a purely professional relationship,
一年只会见几面
only seeing each other a few times a year.
真的吗
Really?
我觉得这很奇怪
I find that strange.
诺里斯先生经常向我姑妈提到贝德伯勒先生
Mr Norris is always mentioning Mr Bedborough  to my aunt.
他们俩亲密无间得很
He made out the two were thick as thieves,
当然 这也有可能不是真的
although that may not have been true, of course.
毕竟他暗恋我姑妈
He may have been trying to impress
他可能是想给她留下深刻印象
since he was secretly in love with her.
哈蒂 我们可以五分钟之内不提你姑妈吗
Hattie, can we go 5 minutes without mentioning your aunt?
当然可以 我道歉
Yes, of course. My apologies.
你说诺里斯和贝德伯勒亲密无间
You said Norris and Bedborough were thick as thieves?
据我所知 他们每个月都在一起吃几次饭
It is my understanding that they dined together several times a month.
诺里斯总是为贝德伯勒先生帮大大小小的忙
and Mr Norris was always doing this favor or that for Mr Bedborough.
我猜诺里斯先生
I believe that Mr Norris
最近打算买骑士桥的房子
recently arranged the purchase of the house in Knightsbridge.
离这里只有几家之遥
It was only a few doors down from...
我要提到我姑妈了 但这是有关的
I'm about to mention my aunt, but I believe it is relevant.
继续
Go on.
贝德伯勒先生的新房子和我姑妈的在一条街上
Mr Bedborough's new house is on the same street as my aunt's.
其他居民都疯狂了
The other residents were beside themselves
有这样一位名人生活在他们中间
to have such a well-known face living among them.
直到
Until...
好吧
Well,
我不是说三道四的人
I am not one to gossip...
当然
Of course...
但请这样做
but please do.
贝德伯勒先生不到两个月前才搬进来
Mr. Bedborough moved in not two months ago.
并且在装修上花了一大笔钱
and seemed to be spending a fortune on illuminations.
收回通知
由于欠债未清 由伦敦市政收回抵押
Samuel Bedborough
但在上周 最离奇的事情发生了
But then last week, the strangest thing happened.
萨缪尔·贝德伯勒负债累累
Samuel Bedborough is up to his neck in debt.
可他住在布拉汉姆酒店的套房里
He's staying a suite at the Brabham.
不会住很久
Not for much longer.
他面临一笔巨额账单
He's facing a hefty bill.
他四处负债
He owes money all over town.
这就是查封官没收房子和房内财产的原因
That's why the bailiffs took his house and everything in it.
而且
And...
他昨晚去查封处了
he be at the bailiff's last night.
去做什么
Doing what?
拿回某件被没收的家具
Trying to get back some piece of furniture that they took from him.
他这周天天 去
Every day this week,
希望把那件家具赎回 但是...
he's turned up trying to buy it back, but...
对方要他要么全部赎买 要么滚蛋
they want the whole bill paid or none.
哪件家具
What piece of furniture?
写作桌
A writing desk.
他告诉他们 没有桌子无法写作
He told them he couldn't write without it.
可他告诉我 他不依赖于灵感和氛围
He told me he had no need for muse or mood,
他可以在任何时间任何地方写作
that he could write any time, any where.
他想把桌子要回来
He wants that desk back.
他昨晚强行闯入仓库 结果被保安抓住
Security caught him breaking into the warehouse last night,
打了他一顿
roughed him up on it.
他缠着绷带的手
His bandaged hand...
这个仓库
This warehouse,
我想你在那儿也有关系吧
I take it you have contacts there?
我在哪儿都有关系
I have contacts everywhere.
他以前可不是这样
And he seen nothing like that before,
真令人诧异
it was amazing.
晚上好
Good evening.
菲茨罗伊警探
Detective Fitzroy.
你的就寝时间不是已经过了吗
Isn't it past your bedtime?
笑话不错
Very good.
各位是否要来一杯
Would anyone like a drink?
他们在这儿不卖牛奶
Oh, they don't serve milk in here.
我就当你说不了
I'll take that as a no.
你怎么不回家找妈咪呢 菲茨罗伊
Why don't you go home to your mommy, Fitzroy,
这样妈咪能帮你洗澡澡
so she can clean you up?
你怎么不闭嘴呢 菲尔普斯
Why don't you shut your mouth, Phelps!
你敢不敢再重复一遍
You want to repeat that?
我想你不敢
I didn't think so.
被宠坏的小混蛋
Spoiled little brat.
你会后悔的 小子
You shouldn't have done that... boy.
换班前 我们有十分钟
We've got 10 minutes until the shifts change.
他的东西在这儿
His things are over there,
他们从他房子里拿走了一切
they took everything from his house.
他们搜刮得一丝不剩
They don't miss a trick, those boys.
怪不得他欠债如此
It's no wonder he is in debt,
此人品位颇为奢侈
the man has expensive tastes.
这些来自皮卡迪利大街的商铺
These are from makers of Piccadilly.
这儿
Here.
看起来不贵啊
Doesn't look like much.
确实不贵
It's not.
他一定非常喜爱这桌子 才会处心积虑地要拿回去
He must be very attached to it if he is that desperate to get it back.
可能有纪念意义
Maybe sentimental.
哈珀克拉底
Harpocrates.
什么
What?
贝德伯勒早期的一篇小说中
In one of Bedborough's early novels,
有个律师 叫哈珀克拉底
there is a lawyer... Harpocrates.
希腊神话中的沉默之神
It is the Greek God of silence.
根据神话 所有他知道的秘密
Legend has it... that whatever secrets he knows.
他都不会泄露
he will never speak of them.
他会将秘密带入坟墓
He will take them to the grave.
但很显然 他的秘密被发现了
but of course, his secrets are discovered...
《独行格林威治》
Alone in Greenwich.
《女巫的呼唤》
Witches Call.
这些是贝德伯勒的小说
These are Bedborough's novels.
上面都是注释和改写
Covered in notes and reworkings.
这应该是最初的手稿
These must be the orignial manuscripts.
为什么要藏起来
Why keep them hidden?
有什么要报告的吗
Anything to report?
没有 长官
No, sir.
贝德伯勒先生怎么样
How is Bedborough?
他在写作 要求不被打扰
He is writing and asked not to be disturbed.
他在哪里
Where is he?
到底怎么了
What the Hell is going on?
我也这么想
My thoughts. Exactly.
我需要确认一个疑点
I needed to confirm a suspicion.
不能浪费时间了 我们得走了
There's no time to waste, we need to go.
去哪里
Where?
书中最后一场死亡 是作者自杀
The final death in the book is when the author takes his own life.
所以我们不能让他没人看守
Then we can't leave him unguarded.
作者不是他
He's not the author.
完结
贝德伯勒小姐
Miss Bedborough!
把刀放下
Put the knife down.
照做吧
Do as he says.
拜托了
Please.
你哥哥家中被拿走的写作桌
The writing desk that was taken from your brother's home...
是你的吗
that was yours?
是的
Yes.
我发现手稿中的批注是书商写给你的
I found manuscripts inside with notes from the publisher addressed to you.
所以这些小说是你写的
So it was you who wrote the novels,
而不是你哥哥
Not your brother.
我们的母亲死于救济所
Our mother died in the workhouse.
我们的父亲
Our father...
他不知所踪
God knows where he went.
萨缪尔希望出人头地
Samuel was determined to make something of himself,
但他奋斗多年 想成为小说家而不得
but he struggled for years to become a novelist.
我不忍心告诉他真相
I didn't have the heart to tell him the truth.
他没有写作才能
That he lacked the talent.
他也知道
He knew it, too.
内心深处知道
Deep down.
但他是我哥哥
But he's my older brother,
为了帮他 我什么都可以做
I would have done anything to help him.
我也确实这么做了
So I did.
我重写了他的故事
I rewrote his story.
我发现自己略有天赋
I found I had a flair for it.
等我把他的手稿交给书商的时候
By the time I submitted his manuscript to publishers,
他写的字句已经所剩无几
there was barely a word of his left.
那你为何不署自己的名字
Why do you put your own name on the cover?
萨缪尔求我不要署名
Samuel begged me not to.
他承受不了这种侮辱
He cannot have suffered the humiliation
负责养家糊口的是他嫁不出去的妹妹 而不是他
that his spinster sister was the one putting food on the table and not him.
但当小说逐渐获得名气后
But after the success of the book started to rise,
我确实问过他 能不能让我署名第二作者
I did ask him if I could put my name to the next.
于是他们开了个会
That was when they called the meeting.
他们
They?
萨缪尔 贝拉米和诺里斯
Samuel, Bellamy and Norris.
他们三个说 由于我是女人
The three of them convinced me that as a woman,
我的薪酬只有男人的一半
my wage would be half of that as a man.
他们承诺总有一天我能以本名写作
They promised that one day I could write under my own name, but
现在时机不对
that was not the right time.
但永远没有对的时机
It was never... the right time.
为什么杀了他们
Why kill them?
在他们的安排里 我的一项福利
The one benefit I received from this arrangement
就是会得到优渥的照顾
was that I would be well looked after.
我应当衣食无忧 安心生活
I would have a comfortable home and security.
但有一天
But then one day
查封官找上门 我才发现真相
the bailiffs arrived and I found out the truth.
萨缪尔的债务太大
Samuel's debts were all consuming.
他把我挣的每一个子都花干净了
He'd spent every penny of my money.
诺里斯一直都知道 但他什么都没做
And Norris knew all along, he did nothing.
他们不在乎
They didn't care.
只要书有人写
As long as the books were still being written
他们就收得到钱
and they were receiving their money.
我替他们挣的钱
Money I was earning for them.
所以这是你的复仇
So this was your revenge?
然后全世界都会知道 你才是真正的作者
And the world would know that you were the true author.
我死去之日 就是我成名之时
I would have my moment of fame in death.
这么长时间以来
All this time
我让哥哥发光发热
I have let my brother shine
我得到了什么
for what?
沦落成贫穷的老姑娘
To end up a poor spinster...
重返救济所
back in a workhouse.
需要我找人捎你回家吗
Would you like me to arrange a lift home?
不用了 谢谢
No, thank you.
我本要自己送你
I would take you myself, but there are
但我还有跟早班交接的报告要完成
reports that I have to finish for the morning shift.
我理解
I understand.
伊莱莎 所有...
Eliza, all this...
所有礼貌客气都让人精疲力尽
All this politeness is exhausting.
可不是么
Isn't it just.
我说你有父亲的事业可以继承 是言不由衷
I didn't mean what I said about your father's business.
我知道你并非坐享其成
I know you haven't been handed anything on a plate.
我知道你工作多么努力
I know how hard you've worked.
只是有时候你刺激我过度
But there are times when you push me too far.
我调侃你 只是因为我在咱们的友谊中非常放松
I only tease you because I'm so comfortable in our friendship.
也许有时候我不该那么敏感
I suppose I can be a little insensitive sometimes.
只是因为我嫉妒
It's only because I'm envious.
嫉妒 嫉妒我吗
Envious? Of me?
你对自己的生活很满意
You are fulfilled in your life.
并不是缺乏上进心
That's not lack of ambition.
这是你应该庆祝的
That's something you should celebrate.
你有着大多数人毕生都无法拥有的珍稀品格
You have that rare thing that most of us don't find in a lifetime.
真正的满足
True contentment.
所以 你是我最尊敬的人之一
That's why you're one of the people I respect most.
你说 "之一"
When you say... one of?
原谅我 长官 我不知道您还在这儿
Forgive me sir... I didn't know you were still here.
你又做了什么
What have you done now?
我听从您的建议
I did as you suggest.
我去了酒馆 试着融入团体
I went for a drink and I tried to fit in.
但我可能尝试过头了
Perhaps I tried a little too hard.
我不能这样回家面对父亲
I could not go home to my father like this, so...
我想我可以睡在这里
I thought I could sleep here.
我有个空余的房间
I have a spare room.
你可以住在那儿
You can stay there.
谢谢你 长官
Thank you, sir.
- 亚历克斯 - 您好啊
- Alex. - Hi, there.
给
Here.
早上好 公爵
G' morning, Duke.
早上好 乔治
G' morning, George.
谢谢公爵 慢走 公爵
Cheers, Duke. Thanks, Duke.
谢谢公爵
Cheers, Duke.
薇尔莉特.
Violet.
- 各位 - 公爵
- Gentlemen. - Duke.
伦敦大都会警察厅
苏格兰场
进来
Come.
我能简短说句话吗 长官
Can I have a quick word, sir?
我可以见你 我基本上完事了
I can see you, I'm almost done.
您旅途如何 长官
How was your trip, sir?
别提了
Don't ask.
- 出差还是旅游 - 都不是
- Business or pleasure? - Neither.
在我夫人娘家待了两天
It was two days at my wife's family.
所以你有充分的时间考虑
So you have had time to think.
我相信你能意识到这次提拔的机会多么好
I trust you realize how good an opportunity this promotion is.
我知道的
I have.
您说得对 是个好机会
And you're right. It's a good opportunity.
不过现阶段的我
But it's not one that's right for me...
不适合 长官
at the moment, sir.
我为这次提拔动用了不少关系
I pulled in a lot of favors to get you this, laddie.
这样的机会可能再不会有
A chance like this may not come up again.
我明白 长官 但我已下决心
I understand, sir, but my decision is made.
我的生活在伦敦这里
My life is here in London.
我本希望你能接受调动
Well, I hoped you would accept the position
有些话就不用跟你说了
so I could avoid this...
长官
Sir?
菲茨罗伊的父亲
Fitzroy's father,
总监希望你离开
the police commissioner wants you gone.
那男孩每况愈下
The boy is getting worse, not better.
我一直在尽力
I been trying.
他是个麻烦
He's an albatross,
这就是为什么我告诉你要跟他保持距离
which is why I told you to put some distance between yourself and him
让他生死由命
to let him sink or swim.
但你不听我的
But you wouldn't listen to me.
现在他没救了 他父亲要找个替罪羊
Now he is drowning and his father wants someone to blame.
所以让我说清楚
So let me be crystal clear.
你要接受格拉斯哥的岗位
You're going to take this post in Glasgow...
因为你在这里已经没有位置了
because there is no longer a job for you here.
■
更多精彩 请登录深影论坛 shinybbs.vip
深影字幕组微博 weibo.com/syfansub
■
关注深影字幕组
微信公众号，更
多影视资讯，等
你来发现